jihadwatch.org 2019-12-17

# Privacy

Jan 11th 2019

At jihadwatch.org (www.jihadwatch.org), the privacy of our visitors is extremely important. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected and how it is used.

This Privacy Policy is reviewed and revised from time to time. You will want to revisit it regularly. Your use of this site, in any and all forms, constitutes an acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

1\. Log Files

We use log files like many other websites. The information in the log files include:

Internet Protocol addresses (IP)  
Types of browser  
Internet Service Provider (ISP)  
Date and time stamp  
Pages visited and the method used  
Referring and exit pages  
Number of clicks  
All of this information is not linked to anything that is personally identifiable.

We will use this logged data to combat malicious abuse and to improve usability for our visitors, and for no other purpose.

Encrypted log files are stored with a cloud hosting provider (off site) for a period of 6 weeks, at which time they are deleted and the storage space overwritten.

2\. Cookies

We use cookies to store information about visitor preferences and to record user-specific information on visits and pages the user views so as to provide a custom experience. In regard to third-party advertisers, we have no access or control over these cookies. You should review the respective privacy policies on any and all third-party ad servers for more information regarding their practices and how to opt-out.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your web browser options. Instructions for doing so and for other cookie-related management can be found on the specific web browsers’ websites. You may access Our Site without providing any data at all, and the use of a VPN for privacy and security is encouraged.

3\. Legal disclosure

In certain circumstances We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal information, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with the requirements of legislation, a court order, or a governmental authority. We do not require any further consent from you in order to share your data in such circumstances and will comply as required with any legally binding request that is made of Us.

4\. Other

Users might be asked to subscribe to our newsletter by providing name and email address to receive communications from jihadwatch.org. We use a secure op-in subscription system and we reserve the right to contact subscribers with information related to this website and blog. Subscribers may unsubscribe anytime and every email delivered will contain an “Unsubscribe” link.

If you subscribe to follow up comments, or have email notifications of all post (10+ emails a day) WordPress’s commercial arm automattic.com have access to your name and email address for that purpose.

If you subscribe to the daily digest (a single daily email) mailchimp.com manage that so would have access to your name and email address.

Both automattic.com and mailchimp.com have proven to be apolitical, and not known to be cavalier with users data, both having their reputations intact. Both have their own privacy notices publicly available.

We do at times enforce Javascript to view the site, this script poses no risk to the browser, and is purely used to mitigate DDoS attacks.

You have the legal right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). If the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive we may charge a “reasonable fee” for the administrative costs of complying with the request.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at marc@jihadwatch.org.
